<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:itunes='http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd'>
    <channel>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <copyright>Copyright 2023 Ithaca College Title IX and College Sports Class through the Park School of Communications &amp; High Tops Media</copyright>
        <title>Talking Title IX and College Sports</title>
        <description><![CDATA[<p>As a college athlete, do you know your rights under Title IX, the law that bars discrimination on the basis of gender? As someone who cares about fairness in college sports, do you know what Title IX requires and what it doesn’t require when it is applied to athletics? Join Dr. Ellen J. Staurowsky, her students, and leading experts as we talk about all things Title IX and college sports.</p> <p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>
]]></description>
        <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//</link>
		
        <itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
        
		<itunes:category text='Education'/>
		
		<itunes:author>Ithaca College Title IX and College Sports Class through the Park School of Communications &amp; High Tops Media</itunes:author>
        <itunes:owner>
            <itunes:name>High Tops Media Podcast Administrator</itunes:name>
            <itunes:email>admin@thisstrangeworldpodcast.com</itunes:email>
        </itunes:owner>
		
        <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:type>episodic</itunes:type>
        <item>
            <title>Gender Logics That Shape Women Athlete Experience in Sport</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S04_05_Gender-Logics-That-Shape-Women-Athlete-Experience-in-Sport.mp3' length='85328280' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2025-04-04-Gender-Logics-That-Shape-Women-Athlete-Experience-in-Sport</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Few would dispute the fact that sport as it is organized in the United States and many places around the world is a gendered environment. Structured around a gender binary, the predominant structure of sport is sex segregated. As much as laws like Title IX are generally thought to foster equal access to sport for men and women, the very act of separating places a spotlight on difference. For women athletes developing in such a system, what gender logics shape their sense of who they are and how do they co-construct these logics? In a fascinating autoethnography, Bowling Green State University sport management professor Meredith Flaherty, who is a former NCAA Division I women’s soccer player, professional soccer player and coach at the youth and college levels, reflects on her own experiences through the lens of gender, discourse, and agency. In this episode, we speak with Meredith about her journey as an athlete, coach, and scholar and the insights she has gained by putting her own athletic career under the microscope.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Meredith Flaherty, Assistant Professor, Sport Management, Bowling Green State University</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram and TikTok! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/
https://www.tiktok.com/@talkingtitleix/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>3554</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2025/04/04/Gender-Logics-That-Shape-Women-Athlete-Experience-in-Sport/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>5</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>4</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Advancing Women in College Sport Leadership Roles: A Conversation About the Pipeline Project</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S04_04_Advancing-Women-in-College-Sport-Leadership-Roles-A-Conversation-About-the-Pipeline-Project.mp3' length='98243058' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2025-03-28-Advancing-Women-in-College-Sport-Leadership-Roles-A-Conversation-About-the-Pipeline-Project</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In today’s episode, we are talking about the exciting work being done by University of Louisville associate professor of sport management Meg Hancock and her colleagues, Nick Kopka and Ehren Green.  They created The Pipeline Project, which is an expansive study of the state of women in intercollegiate athletic administration, documenting where progress has been made for women in athletic administration, points in the industry that call for greater attention and change, and how to advance women in athletics administration.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Dr. Meg Hancock, Associate Professor, Sport Management, University of Louisville; Nick Kopka, Doctoral Student, University of Louisville</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram and TikTok! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/
https://www.tiktok.com/@talkingtitleix/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>4093</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2025/03/28/Advancing-Women-in-College-Sport-Leadership-Roles-A-Conversation-About-the-Pipeline-Project/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>4</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>4</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Women Coach: A Conversation with Vanessa Fuchs, CEO, WeCOACH</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S04_03_Women-Coach-A-Conversation-with-Vanessa-Fuchs-CEO-WeCOACH.mp3' length='70877439' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2025-03-21-Women-Coach-A-Conversation-with-Vanessa-Fuchs-CEO-WeCOACH</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode, we discuss the status of women in college coaching with Vanessa Fuchs, CEO of WeCOACH, an organization that is dedicated  to recruiting, advancing, and retaining women coaches in all sports at all levels through year-round professional growth and leadership development programs.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Vanessa Fuchs, CEO, WeCOACH</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram and TikTok! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/
https://www.tiktok.com/@talkingtitleix/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>2952</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2025/03/21/Women-Coach-A-Conversation-with-Vanessa-Fuchs-CEO-WeCOACH/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>3</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>4</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Title IX as a Point of Convergence: Media, Law, Commerce, and College Sport</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S04_02_Title-IX-as-a-Point-of-Convergence-Media-Law-Commerce-and-College-Sport.mp3' length='38368954' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2025-03-14-Title-IX-as-a-Point-of-Convergence-Media-Law-Commerce-and-College-Sport</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode, we talk about the critical role storytelling plays in creating narratives that affect decisions that impact women college athletes, how the public views and engages with women college athletes, and how women college athletes tell their own stories.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Shannon Scovel is an assistant professor of journalism and media at the University of Tennessee with a research focus on sports media and athlete branding</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram and TikTok! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/
https://www.tiktok.com/@talkingtitleix/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>2397</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2025/03/14/Title-IX-as-a-Point-of-Convergence-Media-Law-Commerce-and-College-Sport/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>2</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>4</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Role College Athletics Plays in Enrollment at Small Private Institutions and Gender Equity Implications</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S04_01_The-Role-College-Athletics-Plays-in-Enrollment-at-Small-Private-Institutions-and-Gender-Equity-Implications.mp3' length='54354981' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2025-02-28-The-Role-College-Athletics-Plays-in-Enrollment-at-Small-Private-Institutions-and-Gender-Equity-Implications</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>For those familiar with the history of college sport and higher education, athletics has played a key role in admission and enrollment efforts in colleges and universities since the late 1800s to the present. In the very early days when land grant institutions like LSU and private colleges like Stanford or Notre Dame were getting established, men’s sports programs became vehicles to attract new applicants and to create name brand recognition. In describing the relationship of athletics to a college campus, Scott Barnes, then athletic director at Utah State University in 2009 offered the metaphor that “Athletics are the front porch of the university. It’s not the most important room in the house, but it is the most visible”. For small private institutions in the 21st century, athletics has increasingly become a critical consideration in enrollment planning. From a strategic perspective, some schools have added men’s sports to respond to declining interest from male applicants. Other schools have added both men’s and women’s teams as part of what is a sports enrollment strategy to build enrollment. And still others gambled on sports enrollment as a survival strategy and lost. To help us gain a better understanding of how “sports enrollment” fits within a larger enrollment strategy for small private colleges, we are joined today by Dr. Steve Dittmore. Steve is dean of the College of Education and Human Services with the University of North Florida.</p>

<p>Dr. Dittmore is a seasoned administrator who is a nationally recognized thought leader on issues related to intercollegiate athletic administration. His primary academic research areas include the role of athletics within higher education, Olympic and college sport policy and governance, government regulation of sport broadcasting and baseball history. He has been the assistant editor and content creator for AthleticDirectorU college athletics news platform and holds prior sport industry practitioner experience with a variety of high-profile organizations. He has authored numerous books and research articles on the industry, including a forthcoming biography Jim Gilliam: The Forgotten Dodger and his substack newsletter, Glory Days.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Dr. Steven Dittmore, Dean, College of Education and Human Services, University of North Florida</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram and TikTok! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/
https://www.tiktok.com/@talkingtitleix/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>3396</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2025/02/28/The-Role-College-Athletics-Plays-in-Enrollment-at-Small-Private-Institutions-and-Gender-Equity-Implications/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>1</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>4</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Political Forces Propelling Flag Football as a Preferred Women's College Sport</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S03_09_The-Political-Forces-Propelling-Flag-Football-as-a-Preferred-Womens-College-Sport.mp3' length='55829051' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2024-05-31-The-Political-Forces-Propelling-Flag-Football-as-a-Preferred-Womens-College-Sport</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode we have the wonderful opportunity to visit with Coach Becky Carlson, the head coach of women’s rugby at Quinnipiac University about an article she recently published on LinkedIn entitled “Flag Football: The Double Standard, the Money, and the Death of Non-Revenue Sports”. Coach Carlson has been the head coach of women’s rugby at Quinnipiac since its inception in 2011, building the program from the ground up and creating a Division I women’s rugby program that in short order won three back to back NIRA championships and has won 70% of its games in the last 13 years.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Becky Carlson (Head Coach of Women’s Rugby at Quinnipiac University)</p>

<p>https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/flag-football-double-standard-money-death-non-revenue-coach-carlson-iwx3e/?trackingId=mK%2BNY0iERV29dJbEUiV1qw%3D%3D</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram and TikTok! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/
https://www.tiktok.com/@talkingtitleix/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>3488</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2024/05/31/The-Political-Forces-Propelling-Flag-Football-as-a-Preferred-Womens-College-Sport/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>9</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>3</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Title IX From an Athletic Director's View</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S03_08_Title-IX-From-an-Athletic-Directors-View.mp3' length='61253052' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2024-05-10-Title-IX-From-an-Athletic-Directors-View</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 02:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode we’ll speak with Renee Carlineo (IC ‘07), who is director of intercollegiate athletics and recreation at Buffalo State University about her professional journey to the AD’s chair, how her early work as a strength and conditioning coach and lacrosse coach and back in sport psychology has advised her approach to leadership and management. We’ll also get into some details on how to develop an approach to Title IX compliance and promoting gender equity within an athletic department.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Renee Carlineo (IC ‘07; Director of Athletics at Buffalo State University)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram and TikTok! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/
https://www.tiktok.com/@talkingtitleix/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>3827</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2024/05/10/Title-IX-From-an-Athletic-Directors-View/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>8</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>3</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Challenging Sex-Segregation in Sport and Exploring the Possibilities of Combined Men's and Women's Competition</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S03_07_Challenging-Sex-Segregation-in-Sport.mp3' length='50939963' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2024-05-03-Challenging-Sex-Segregation-in-Sport</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode we have the wonderful opportunity to speak with Dr. Stephen Gambescia who is a Professor, Health Services Administration &amp; Director, Doctor of Health Science College of Nursing and Health Professions at Drexel University.  He recently published an article in the Delta Epsilon Sigma Journal entitled A Research Agenda for Combined Men and Women Sports Competition.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Dr. Stephen Gambescia (Professor, Health Services Administration &amp; Director, Doctor of Health Science College of Nursing and Health Professions at Drexel University)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram and TikTok! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/
https://www.tiktok.com/@talkingtitleix/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>3183</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2024/05/03/Challenging-Sex-Segregation-in-Sport/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>7</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>3</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A Conversation with Boxer and Poet, Raisa Tolchinsky</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S03_06_A-Conversation-with-Boxer-and-Poet-Raisa-Tolchinsky.mp3' length='34621499' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2024-04-26-A-Conversation-with-Boxer-and-Poet-Raisa-Tolchinsky</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode we learn about the powerful and affecting journey of Raisa Tolchinsky, a boxer and poet who delivers in her collection of poems, <em>Glass Jaw</em>, the complexities so many women boxers and women athletes encounter in a space where liberation and empowerment is often abused.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Raisa Tolchinsky (Boxer and Poet, Author of <em>Glass Jaw</em>)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram and TikTok! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/
https://www.tiktok.com/@talkingtitleix/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>2163</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2024/04/26/A-Conversation-with-Boxer-and-Poet-Raisa-Tolchinsky/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>6</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>3</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Women in Sport Leadership Encountering the Glass Ceiling and the Glass Cliff</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S03_05_Women-in-Sport-Leadership-Encountering-the-Glass-Ceiling-and-the-Glass-Cliff.mp3' length='66193214' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2024-04-19-Women-in-Sport-Leadership-Encountering-the-Glass-Ceiling-and-the-Glass-Cliff</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode we discuss the perceptions of women working in leadership roles in the sports industry, the experiences they have with the glass ceiling and glass cliff and the perceptions aspiring women professionals have of their prospects for becoming leaders in sport.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Meg Hancock (Professor at University of Louisville)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram and TikTok! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/
https://www.tiktok.com/@talkingtitleix/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>4136</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2024/04/19/Women-in-Sport-Leadership-Encountering-the-Glass-Ceiling-and-the-Glass-Cliff/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>5</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>3</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Women College Athletes and Mental Health</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S03_04_Women-College-Athletes-and-Mental-Health.mp3' length='57092411' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2024-04-12-Women-College-Athletes-and-Mental-Health</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 01:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode we discuss ongoing concern about women college athletes and mental health.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Rick Eckstein (Professor of Sociology at Villanova University and Author of <em>How College Athletics Are Hurting Girls’ Sports: The Pay-to-Play Pipeline</em>)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram and TikTok! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/
https://www.tiktok.com/@talkingtitleix/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>3567</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2024/04/12/Women-College-Athletes-and-Mental-Health/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>4</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>3</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Reframing NCAA Marketing Approaches to Women's Sports</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S03_03_Reframing-NCAA-Marketing-Approaches-to-Womens-Sports.mp3' length='43705018' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2024-04-05-Reframing-NCAA-Marketing-Approaches-to-Womens-Sports</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 03:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>This episode focuses on initiatives college athlete departments can take to cultivate investment in women’s sports by reconnecting and celebrating the accomplishments of women athletes from previous eras with current women athletes. The University of Oregon’s Women in Flight serve as case examples of what can be accomplished by reframing promotional efforts and embracing past, present, and future generations of women college athletes.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Colleen Dibble (Academic Coach and Doctoral Student, University of South Carolina)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram and TikTok! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/
https://www.tiktok.com/@talkingtitleix/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>2730</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2024/04/05/Reframing-NCAA-Marketing-Approaches-to-Womens-Sports/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>3</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>3</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Writing Women Into and Out of Sports Coverage</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S03_02_Writing-Women-Into-and-Out-of-Sports-Coverage.mp3' length='49814203' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2024-03-29-Writing-Women-Into-and-Out-of-Sports-Coverage</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 02:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In our interview with one of the most prolific women’s sports writers in the United States, we explore the amnesia and neglect sports writers often have about women’s sports history through the little known story of the National Women’s Football League, brought to light by sports writer Lyndsey D’Arcangelo and their co-author, Frankie De La Cretaz.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Lyndsey D’Arcangelo (Sports Writer)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram and TikTok! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/
https://www.tiktok.com/@talkingtitleix/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>3112</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2024/03/29/Writing-Women-Into-and-Out-of-Sports-Coverage/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>2</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>3</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Women College Athletes and Advocating for Their Rights Under Title IX</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S03_01_Women-College-Athletes-and-the-Steps-They-Can-Take.mp3' length='64357297' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2024-03-22-Women-College-Athletes-and-the-Steps-They-Can-Take</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 02:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In the Season 3 premiere of Talking Title IX and College Sports, we focus on steps women college athletes can take to advocate for their rights under Title IX within their own athletic departments.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Emlyn Patry (Graduate of Trinity College, Who Advocated for Equal Treatment for Women Athletes on Her Campus)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram and TikTok! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/
https://www.tiktok.com/@talkingtitleix/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>4021</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2024/03/22/Women-College-Athletes-and-the-Steps-They-Can-Take/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>1</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>3</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A Conversation About the Equal Distance Initiative With St. Michael’s Head Nordic Ski and Cross Country Coach, Molly Peters</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S02_10_A-Conversation-About-the-Equal-Distance-Initiative.mp3' length='31668928' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-12-15-A-Conversation-About-the-Equal-Distance-Initiative</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:25:00 -0500</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode, we are visiting with Molly Peters to talk about her work advocating for equal treatment for women athletes in the sport of cross country. At present, in 2023, men run distances between 8 to 10K and women run distances between 5-6 K. Why is this? Molly Peters is founder of Equal Distance and head coach at Saint Michael’s College in Vermont and is here to help us answer that question. 
For more information about the Equal Distance Initiative go to https://equaldistance.org</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Molly Peters (Founder of Equal Distance; St. Michael’s Head Nordic Ski and Cross Country Coach)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>1978</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/12/15/A-Conversation-About-the-Equal-Distance-Initiative/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>10</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>2</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A Conversation With Macaela MacKenzie, Author of Money, Power, Respect: How Women's Sports is Shaping the Future of Feminism</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S02_09_A-Conversation-With-Macaela-MacKenzie.mp3' length='51721021' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-12-08-A-Conversation-With-Macaela-MacKenzie</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode, we are so fortunate to visit with Macaela MacKenzie, a journalist who writes about women and power.  She covers women’s equality through the lens of sports, wellness, and the gender gap across industries. She was a senior editor at Glamour, and her work has been published in Elle, Self, Marie Claire, Forbes, and Bustle. In the summer of 2023, Macaela published a book entitled Money, Power, Respect: How Women in Sports Are Shaping the Future of Feminism.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Macaela MacKenzie (Journalist, Author of Money, Power, Respect: How Women’s Sports is Shaping the Future of Feminism)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>3231</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/12/08/A-Conversation-With-Macaela-MacKenzie/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>9</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>2</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Sexual Violence Prevention and Education in NCAA Division I Athletic Departments</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S02_08_Sexual-Violence-Prevention-and-Education.mp3' length='52285499' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-12-01-Sexual-Violence-Prevention-and-Education</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Within athletic departments that operate under the umbrella of the NCAA, reports of sexual violence on the part of athletes; coaches; administrators; and donors raise a host of questions about factors that may contribute to cultures of violence and questions regarding Title IX compliance and accountability. To help us sort through some of this, I am pleased to welcome to the show Molly Harry, an assistant professor of sports management with the University of Arkansas and Katrina (Trina) Garry, Deputy Title IX Coordinator with the University of San Francisco. Our conversation today is on a project they did focusing on Challenges and Best Practices for Sexual Violence Prevention and Education in Division I Athletics Departments published in the Journal of Issues in Intercollegiate Athletics.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guests: Molly Harry (Assistant Professor of Sports Management with University of Arkansas) &amp; Trina Garry (Deputy Title IX Coordinator with the University of San Francisco)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>3267</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/12/01/Sexual-Violence-Prevention-and-Education/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>8</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>2</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Factors Affecting College Conference Decision Making and Adding Sports</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S02_07_Factors-Affecting-College-Conference-Decision-Making.mp3' length='51009408' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-11-17-Factors-Affecting-College-Conference-Decision-Making</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>As a general observation, most discussions about Title IX as it applies to athletic departments generally focus on what is happening with individual schools and with national governing bodies like the NCAA.  In this episode we talk about the oft overlooked role college conferences play in shaping athletic departments because conferences decide what sports will be supported in terms of championship competition.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Sloane Milstein (Associate Professor of Sports Management with Colorado Mesa University) &amp; Julie Lanzillo (Program Director and Associate Professor in the Sport Management Program at Neumann University)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>3188</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/11/17/Factors-Affecting-College-Conference-Decision-Making/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>7</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>2</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Accelerating Equity by Making Title IX Data Available to the Public</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S02_06_Accelerating-Equity.mp3' length='48882432' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-11-10-Accelerating-Equity</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode, we are visiting with Pam Seidenman, Founder and Executive Director of Accelerate Equity, a non-profit that she is launching to increase gender equity in collegiate athletics. Pam is also the Development Director at the California Policy Lab at UC Berkeley and UCLA. Pam has raised over $30 million to support social and technical innovation, and has worked with multiple organizations that use data to drive policy change.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Pam Seidenman (Founder and Executive Director of Accelerate Equity)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>3055</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/11/10/Accelerating-Equity/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>6</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>2</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Addressing Title IX Shortfalls: The Case of Women's Lacrosse at Florida State</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S02_05_Addressing-Title-IX-Shortfalls.mp3' length='42202752' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-10-27-Addressing-Title-IX-Shortfalls</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode, we talk with woman athlete activist and Florida State University (FSU) women’s lacrosse player Sophia Villalonga and attorney Lori Bullock of Bailey Glasser. After an investigative report published in USA Today revealed that FSU was not providing equitable opportunities for women athletes under Title IX, Sophia led an effort assisted by Lori and her colleague, Arthur Bryant, to elevate women’s lacrosse to varsity status. In October of 2023, FSU announced that a varsity women’s lacrosse program was expected to debut in the spring of 2026 and that they had a commitment to creating a gender equity process to ensure that the interests of women athletes at FSU are protected.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Sophia Villalonga (Florida State Women’s Lacrosse Player) &amp; Lori Bullock, J.D. (Bailey &amp; Glasser Attorney)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>2637</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/10/27/Addressing-Title-IX-Shortfalls/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>5</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>2</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A Conversation With Libby Sharrow, Co-Author of Equality Unfulfilled</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S02_04_A-Conversation-With-Libby-Sharrow.mp3' length='53978496' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-10-20-A-Conversation-With-Libby-Sharrow</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode, we talk with Dr. Libby Sharrow, co-author of new book, Equality Unfulfilled: How Title IX’s Policy Design Undermines Change in College Sports.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Libby Sharrow (Co-Author of Equality Unfulfilled)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>3373</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/10/20/A-Conversation-With-Libby-Sharrow/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>4</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>2</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>College Athletes Compensation Issues: The Current Status of In re: College Athlete NIL Litigation</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S02_03_College-Athletes-Compensation-Issues.mp3' length='42583296' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-10-13-College-Athletes-Compensation-Issues</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 01:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In a case currently pending in the US District Court in Northern California before Judge Claudia Wilkens, multiple college athletes have challenged the NCAA and the Power Five Conferences for retroactive compensation they were denied as a result of the NCAA’s restrictive compensation rules and share of revenue produced from broadcast rights. This case is being watched closely because of what a favorable ruling would mean for college athletes and how this might affect the business of college sport moving forward. To help us break down this case and talk through these arguments that are being presented on both sides, today we have Matt Netti, an associate with Nixon Peabody who focuses on employment counseling, representing employers in litigation and labor negotiations, and a wide variety of general labor and employment matters.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Matt Netti (Associate with Nixon Peabody, Ithaca College Alumni)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>2661</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/10/13/College-Athletes-Compensation-Issues/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>3</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>2</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Pregnancy Discrimination and College Sports After 50 Years of Title IX</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S02_02_Pregnancy-Discrimination.mp3' length='50233405' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-10-06-Pregnancy-Discrimination</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 01:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode, we focus on an often under-reported but incredibly important part of the lives of college athletes, that being the group of women athletes who are expectant mothers and women and men athletes who are parents. To help us talk through these things today and to understand the dynamics around the access college athletes have to information about their rights relative to pregnancy and parenting under Title IX and NCAA bylaws as well as policy, we have two special guests, Dr. David McArdle and Dr. Sylvia de Mars.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guests: Dr. David McArdle (Senior Lecturer in the School of Law at Stirling University, Scotland) &amp; Dr. Sylvia de Mars (Reader in Transnational Public Law at Newcastle University School of Law in England)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>3138</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/10/06/Pregnancy-Discrimination/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>2</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>2</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Demand IX Campaign: Empowering the Next Generation of Title IX Advocates</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S02_01_The-Demand-IX-Campaign.mp3' length='50159412' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-09-29-The-Demand-IX-Campaign</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In the opening episode of Season 2, we had the opportunity to speak with three amazing women - Mary Ciampa, Tiffany Bullock, and Arla Davis. These three Title IX champions  have been doing incredible work in educating and empowering the next generation of Title IX advocates through the WomenX Demand IX Campaign.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guests: Mary Ciampa (Board of Advisory roles at Boston Museum of Science and Berklee College of Music Online), Tiffany Bullock (Diversity inclusion roles at Friend, Frank, Harris, Shriver &amp; Jacobson LLP &amp; SEO Law), Arla Davis (2023 Park School of Communications graduate &amp; intern for Demand IX)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>Follow for more High Tops Media content on Instagram:
https://www.instagram.com/hightopsmedia/
Check out more podcasts from HTM on our website: https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>3134</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/09/29/The-Demand-IX-Campaign/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>1</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>2</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>A Conversation About Trans Inclusion in Sport in Title IX's 50th Anniversary Year</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S01_12_A-Conversation-About-Trans-Inclusion-in-Sport.mp3' length='123419859' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-07-21-A-Conversation-About-Trans-Inclusion-in-Sport</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 03:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode we examined issues related to ongoing conversations regarding transgender athlete experience in sport, efforts to make sport a more inclusive space for transgender athletes, and increasing efforts on the part of state entities to regulate and control how, when, and under what circumstances transgender athletes compete in sport.</p>

<p>Panelists: Anna Baeth, Ph.D. (she/her), critical feminist scholar and a cultural studies practitioner of sport. Director of Research, Athlete Ally; assistant field hockey coach, Mount Holyoke College</p>

<p>August Donato, IC ’26, Men’s Rugby Team</p>

<p>Vikki Krane, Ph.D., (they/them), Professor, Human Movement, Sport, and Leisure Studies, Bowling Green State University and editor, Sex, Gender, and Sexuality in Sport: Queer Inquiries</p>

<p>Luca Maurer, Interim Executive Director, Student Equity and Belonging, and Director, Center for LGBT Education, Outreach &amp; Service and will soon serve as Executive Director of Student Equity, Inclusion, and Belonging</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>You can follow for more High Tops Media content on Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter: @hightopsmedia<br />
Check out more podcasts on our website https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>5142</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/07/21/A-Conversation-About-Trans-Inclusion-in-Sport/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>12</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Reproductive Rights of Women Athletes in Title IX's 50th Anniversary Year and Post-Dobbs</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S01_11_Reproductive-Rights-of-Women-Athletes.mp3' length='123416649' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-07-14-Reproductive-Rights-of-Women-Athletes</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode we examined issues related to the reproductive rights of women athletes beginning with a brief historical perspective on the tensions around perceived risks and threats that sports participation posed for women in the late 19th and 20th centuries and issues women athletes face in the 21st century including women athletes rights under Title IX in terms of pregnancy and parenting; problematic issues associated with tracking the menstrual cycles of women athletes; and how access to bodily autonomy and reproductive freedom impact women athletes and women’s lives in general.</p>

<p>Panelists: Leila Abolfazli, J.D., Director of National Strategy on Abortion Rights, National Women’s Law Center</p>

<p>Bayliss Fiddiman, J.D., Director of Educational Equity, Senior Counsel, National Women’s Law Center</p>

<p>Lindsey Darvin, Ph.D., Assistant Professor, Syracuse University</p>

<p>Jaime Schultz, Ph.D., Sport Historian, Professor, The Pennsylvania State University</p>

<p>Elizabeth Sorensen, Ph.D., R.N., professor, Wright State University and co-author, NCAA Pregnancy and Parenting</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>You can follow for more High Tops Media content on Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter: @hightopsmedia<br />
Check out more podcasts on our website https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>5142</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/07/15/Reproductive-Rights-of-Women-Athletes/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>11</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Title IX Through the Lens of Gender and Race Intersectionality: Not All Women Athletes Benefit Equally</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S01_10_Title-IX-Through-the-Lens-of-Gender-and-Race-Intersectionality.mp3' length='86475865' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-07-07-Title-IX-Through-the-Lens-of-Gender-and-Race-Intersectionality</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The focus of this episode was on the barriers to participation and work that Black women encounter in the U.S. college sport system, the effects of racial clustering, the experiences of Black women athletes, coaches, and athletics administrators, and steps to promote gender and racial equity in the college sport space.</p>

<p>Moderator: Dr. Ellen J. Staurowsky</p>

<p>Panelists: Kirsten Hextrum, Ph.D., Assistant Professor of Language, Culture, and Society; Graduate Faculty in Women, Gender, &amp; Sexuality Studies; and Director of the College Student Services Administration Program, Oregon State University</p>

<p>Katelyn Hutchison, IC SPME &amp; MBA ‘22, Master’s Candidate – Sport Leadership and Member, Women’s Track &amp; Field, University of Kentucky</p>

<p>Joyce Olushola Ogunrinde, Ph.D., Assistant Professor, Kinesiology-Sport Management, University of Houston</p>

<p>F. Michelle Richardson, Ph.D., Associate Professor, Sport Management, Coppin State &amp; President, North American Society for the Sociology of Sport</p>

<p>Erienne Roberts, J.D., Deputy Athletics Director, Ithaca College</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>You can follow for more High Tops Media content on Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter: @hightopsmedia<br />
Check out more podcasts on our website https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>5404</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/07/07/Title-IX-Through-the-Lens-of-Gender-and-Race-Intersectionality/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>10</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Future of Women's Sports Media Coverage</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S01_09_The-Future-of-Womens-Sports-Media-Coverage.mp3' length='89520581' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-06-30-The-Future-of-Womens-Sports-Media-Coverage</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode, we explored barriers to women’s sports media coverage, new ways of thinking about women’s sports media coverage, how the lack of sports media coverage affects women’s sports, and how to unlock opportunities for greater and better sports media coverage of women’s sports.</p>

<p>Moderator: Arla Davis (SPME ‘23)</p>

<p>Panelists: Carol Stiff, former VP of Programming and Acquisitions, ESPN; President of the Board of Directors, Women’s Basketball Hall of Fame; and Chair, Women’s Sports Network Board of Advisors</p>

<p>Deborah Stroman, Ph.D., CLU, Professor University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill (Director, Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion in Research Program and Faculty Advisor, Carolina Sport Business Club); Entrepreneur, Center of Sport Business and Analytics</p>

<p>Dunja Antunovic, Ph.D., Assistant Professor, Sport Sociology, University of Minnesota</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>You can follow for more High Tops Media content on Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter: @hightopsmedia<br />
Check out more podcasts on our website https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>5594</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/06/30/The-Future-of-Womens-Sports-Media-Coverage/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>9</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Women and Men College Athletes Losing Out on Their Fair Share of Opportunities and Scholarships</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S01_08_Women-and-Men-College-Athletes-Losing-Out_Re-Edit.mp3' length='75802628' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-06-23-Women-and-Men-College-Athletes-Losing-Out</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode we spoke with Arthur Bryant, an attorney who has represented more women athletes and potential women athletes in Title IX litigation than any other lawyer in the country. We looked closely at the topic of women college athletes losing out on their fair share of opportunities and athletic scholarships as well as how Title IX can also apply to men athletes.</p>

<p>Co-Hosts: Evan Glotzer (SPME ‘23); Dustin Terry (SPME ‘23); Dr. Ellen J. Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Arthur Bryant, J.D., an attorney with Bailey Glasser who has represented more women athletes and potential women athletes in Title IX litigation than any other lawyer in the country; he is chair emeritus of Public Justice, one of the nation’s leading public interest law firms; he received the Legacy Award from Public Justice in 2021; also the War Horse Award from the Southern Trial Lawyers Association in 2022 for his extraordinary contributions to the cause of justice; named a Sports Law Trailblazer by the National Law Journal in 2021</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>You can follow for more High Tops Media content on Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter: @hightopsmedia<br />
Check out more podcasts on our website https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>3158</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/06/23/Women-and-Men-College-Athletes-Losing-Out/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>8</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Following the Bouncing Ball: Ways Schools Subvert the Intent of Title IX</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S01_07_Following-the-Bouncing-Ball_Re-Edit.mp3' length='54729793' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-06-16-Following-the-Bouncing-Ball</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode we spoke with Kristen Galles, one of the nation’s most prominent Title IX litigators to learn more about how Title IX applies to athletic departments and to reflect on how, after 50 years since the passage of Title IX, athletic departments are slow to comply with Title IX.</p>

<p>Co-Hosts: Dean Gutic (SPME ‘23); Dr. Ellen J. Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Kristin Galles, J.D., civil rights attorney and recipient of the 2022 Ramey Gender Justice Award; Kristen has been involved in many notable precedent setting Title IX cases such as Communities for Equity v. Michigan High School Athletic Association, Jackson v. Birmingham, Mansourian v. University of California Regents, Biediger v. Quinnipiac University, and Lazar v. UConn</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>You can follow for more High Tops Media content on Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter: @hightopsmedia<br />
Check out more podcasts on our website https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>2280</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/06/16/Following-the-Bouncing-Ball/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>7</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Title IX From a Plaintiff's Perspective: A Conversation with Robin Lamott Sparks</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S01_06_Title-IX-From-a-Plaintiffs-Perspective.mp3' length='67325133' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-06-09-Title-IX-From-a-Plaintiffs-Perspective</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 03:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode, we focus on the case of Biediger v. Quinnipiac. We had the opportunity to speak with Robin Lamott Sparks, the former volleyball coach at Quinnipiac University, who was willing to stand with some of her athletes and challenge her employer in court in order to save her team.</p>

<p>Co-Hosts: Aidan Charde (SPME, ‘23); Dr. Ellen J. Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Robin Lamott Sparks, the former volleyball coach at Quinnipiac University, who was willing to stand with some of her athletes and challenge her employer in court in order to save her team</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>You can follow for more High Tops Media content on Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter: @hightopsmedia<br />
Check out more podcasts on our website https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>2804</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/06/09/Title-IX-From-a-Plaintiffs-Perspective/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>6</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Title IX and Athlete Discipline: The Case of Noriana Radwan v. Ward Manuel and the University of Connecticut</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S01_05_Title-IX-and-Athlete-Discipline.mp3' length='54793670' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-06-02-Title-IX-and-Athlete-Discipline</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode, we examined the case of Noriana Radwan, a former women’s soccer player at the University of Connecticut who lost her athletic scholarship after she made an obscene gesture that was caught on camera. This case raises the basic question about whether women athletes are subjected to different standards in terms of their conduct and do they suffer greater penalties as a result.</p>

<p>Co-Hosts: Jess Moskowitz (Journ ‘23); Dr. Ellen J. Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guests: Plaintiff’s attorneys Greg Tarone J.D. (extensive experience in sports law and athlete representation; he has been an agent and manager for LPGA, NBA, and Olympic athletes); Jonathan Klein, J.D., partner, Parlatore Law Group, Bridgeport Connecticut</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>You can follow for more High Tops Media content on Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter: @hightopsmedia<br />
Check out more podcasts on our website https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>2282</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/06/02/Title-IX-and-Athlete-Discipline/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>5</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Myth of Title IX Cutting Men's Sports</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S01_04_The-Myth-of-Title-IX-Cutting-Mens-Sports.mp3' length='52066115' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-05-26-The-Myth-of-Title-IX-Cutting-Mens-Sports</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 09:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode, we explore one dimension to this mythology that Title IX is responsible for cutting men’s sports, that being what specifically happens when men’s college programs are cut.</p>

<p>Co-Hosts: Kyle DeSantis (SPME ‘23); Jack Henry Cicio (SPME ‘23); Dr. Ellen J. Staurowsky</p>

<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>Guests: Dr. Anne Marx (Loras College); Dr. Joel Cormier (Eastern Kentucky University; co-authors along with Roman Ciapalo of a recently published article in the Journal of Intercollegiate Sport entitled The Financial Impact of Eliminating a NCAA Division</td>
      <td>Men’s Sport on the Athletic Budget: Is Title IX to Blame?)</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>You can follow for more High Tops Media content on Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter: @hightopsmedia<br />
Check out more podcasts on our website https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>2169</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/05/26/The-Myth-of-Title-IX-Cutting-Mens-Sports/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>4</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Title IX and the Contact Sports Exemption</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S01_03_Title-IX-and-the-Contact-Sports-Exemption.mp3' length='44022342' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-05-19-Title-IX-and-the-Contact-Sports-Exemption</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 09:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>For those who follow college sports, a woman playing on a man’s team is not completely unusual but not something you hear about every day either. On March 17, 2023, first year walk-on Olivia Pichardo became the first woman to play in an NCAA Division I baseball game. Interestingly enough, Title IX has something called the contact sports exemption that a school can invoke to keep a woman from playing on some men’s teams, such as baseball. In this episode, we learn more about the contact sports exemption, how Title IX is on a collision course with the Equal Protection Clause of the 14th Amendment when it comes to athletes competing on mixed sex teams, and whether the contact sports exemption should still exist in the 21st century.</p>

<p>Co-Hosts: Jeremy Goldstein (SPME ‘23); Max Adams (SPME ‘23); Isaiah Couzer (Ex ‘25); Dr. Ellen J. Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Dr. Sarah Fields (University of Colorado at Denver and author of Female Gladiators: Gender, Law, and Contact Sport in America)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>You can follow for more High Tops Media content on Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter: @hightopsmedia<br />
Check out more podcasts on our website https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>1833</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/05/19/Title-IX-and-the-Contact-Sports-Exemption/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>3</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Title IX at the Beginning</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S01_02_Title-IX-at-the-Beginning.mp3' length='44639119' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-05-12-02-Title-IX-at-the-Beginning</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 01:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode, we had the opportunity to speak with two of the nation’s leading women’s sports advocates, Dr. Carole Oglesby and Deborah Larkin, who were there at the beginning, before Title IX was passed in 1972. They have both played critically important roles in shaping women’s sport nationally and internationally for over 50 years.</p>

<p>Co-Hosts: Arla Davis (SPME ‘23); Jacob Lentz (SPME ‘23); Dr. Ellen J. Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guests: Dr. Carole Oglesby (the first president of the Association of Intercollegiate Athletics for Women and founder of Women’s Sports International); Deborah Larkin (two-time executive director of the Women’s Sports Foundation and co-founder of Demand IX)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>You can follow for more High Tops Media content on Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter: @hightopsmedia<br />
Check out more podcasts on our website https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>2789</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/05/12/02-Title-IX-at-the-Beginning/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>2</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Title IX Two-Minute Drill: A Primer on Title IX's Application to Athletics</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S01_01_Title-IX-Two-Minute-Drill.mp3' length='20011210' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-05-12-01-Title-IX-Two-Minute-Drill</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>This introductory episode provides a brief overview of Title IX basics as they apply to athletic departments, including the areas Title IX covers (athletic participation, athletically-related aid, and operational resources) and some of the mechanisms used to determine whether a school is complying with Title IX standards.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen J. Staurowsky</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>You can follow for more High Tops Media content on Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter: @hightopsmedia<br />
Check out more podcasts on our website https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>1257</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/05/12/01-Title-IX-Two-Minute-Drill/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>1</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>An Introduction and Welcome to Talking Title IX and College Sports</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S01_00_Trailer1.mp3' length='9002894' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-05-10-Trailer1</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>This spring, students in my Title IX and College Sports class have been studying about Title IX and its application to athletics in the 50th year since Title IX was passed in 1972.  Together we’ve learned about the wonder of Title IX as a comprehensive piece of federal legislation that has, over the years, singularly or in tandem with other equity laws, helped unlock access to educational and athletic opportunities, paving the way for inroads into academic majors and jobs that were once thought of as the exclusive domains of either men or women.  Even as we learn about Title IX’s impact on the ability of students to gain equal access to educational opportunity regardless of gender, the facts about Title IX have also left so many questions unanswered, most specifically why so few Americans in general, and people in college sports in particular - think athletes, coaches, and athletics administrators - know very little about what Title IX is and what it actually requires.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen J. Staurowsky</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>You can follow for more High Tops Media content on Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter: @hightopsmedia<br />
Check out more podcasts on our website https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>374</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/05/10/Trailer1/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>0</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
            <itunes:episodeType>trailer</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>