<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version='2.0' xmlns:content='http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/' xmlns:itunes='http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd'>
    <channel>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <copyright>Copyright 2023 Ithaca College Title IX and College Sports Class through the Park School of Communications &amp; High Tops Media</copyright>
        <title>Talking Title IX and College Sports</title>
        <description><![CDATA[<p>As a college athlete, do you know your rights under Title IX, the law that bars discrimination on the basis of gender? As someone who cares about fairness in college sports, do you know what Title IX requires and what it doesn’t require when it is applied to athletics? Join Dr. Ellen J. Staurowsky, her students, and leading experts as we talk about all things Title IX and college sports.</p> <p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>
]]></description>
        <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//</link>
		
        <itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
        
		<itunes:category text='Education'/>
		
		<itunes:author>Ithaca College Title IX and College Sports Class through the Park School of Communications &amp; High Tops Media</itunes:author>
        <itunes:owner>
            <itunes:name>High Tops Media Podcast Administrator</itunes:name>
            <itunes:email>admin@thisstrangeworldpodcast.com</itunes:email>
        </itunes:owner>
		
        <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:type>episodic</itunes:type>
        <item>
            <title>Title IX and the Contact Sports Exemption</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S01_03_Title-IX-and-the-Contact-Sports-Exemption.mp3' length='44022342' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-05-19-Title-IX-and-the-Contact-Sports-Exemption</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 09:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>For those who follow college sports, a woman playing on a man’s team is not completely unusual but not something you hear about every day either. On March 17, 2023, first year walk-on Olivia Pichardo became the first woman to play in an NCAA Division I baseball game. Interestingly enough, Title IX has something called the contact sports exemption that a school can invoke to keep a woman from playing on some men’s teams, such as baseball. In this episode, we learn more about the contact sports exemption, how Title IX is on a collision course with the Equal Protection Clause of the 14th Amendment when it comes to athletes competing on mixed sex teams, and whether the contact sports exemption should still exist in the 21st century.</p>

<p>Co-Hosts: Jeremy Goldstein (SPME ‘23); Max Adams (SPME ‘23); Isaiah Couzer (Ex ‘25); Dr. Ellen J. Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guest: Dr. Sarah Fields (University of Colorado at Denver and author of Female Gladiators: Gender, Law, and Contact Sport in America)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>You can follow for more High Tops Media content on Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter: @hightopsmedia<br />
Check out more podcasts on our website https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>1833</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/05/19/Title-IX-and-the-Contact-Sports-Exemption/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>3</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Title IX at the Beginning</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S01_02_Title-IX-at-the-Beginning.mp3' length='44639119' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-05-12-02-Title-IX-at-the-Beginning</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 01:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode, we had the opportunity to speak with two of the nation’s leading women’s sports advocates, Dr. Carole Oglesby and Deborah Larkin, who were there at the beginning, before Title IX was passed in 1972. They have both played critically important roles in shaping women’s sport nationally and internationally for over 50 years.</p>

<p>Co-Hosts: Arla Davis (SPME ‘23); Jacob Lentz (SPME ‘23); Dr. Ellen J. Staurowsky</p>

<p>Guests: Dr. Carole Oglesby (the first president of the Association of Intercollegiate Athletics for Women and founder of Women’s Sports International); Deborah Larkin (two-time executive director of the Women’s Sports Foundation and co-founder of Demand IX)</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>You can follow for more High Tops Media content on Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter: @hightopsmedia<br />
Check out more podcasts on our website https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>2789</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/05/12/02-Title-IX-at-the-Beginning/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>2</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Title IX Two-Minute Drill: A Primer on Title IX's Application to Athletics</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S01_01_Title-IX-Two-Minute-Drill.mp3' length='20011210' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-05-12-01-Title-IX-Two-Minute-Drill</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>This introductory episode provides a brief overview of Title IX basics as they apply to athletic departments, including the areas Title IX covers (athletic participation, athletically-related aid, and operational resources) and some of the mechanisms used to determine whether a school is complying with Title IX standards.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen J. Staurowsky</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>You can follow for more High Tops Media content on Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter: @hightopsmedia<br />
Check out more podcasts on our website https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>1257</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/05/12/01-Title-IX-Two-Minute-Drill/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>1</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
            
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>An Introduction and Welcome to Talking Title IX and College Sports</title>
            <enclosure url='https://dts.podtrac.com/redirect.mp3/cdn.thisstrangeworldpodcast.com/file/thisstrangeworldpodcast/TTIX/TTIX_S01_00_Trailer1.mp3' length='9002894' type='audio/mpeg'/>
			<guid>2023-05-10-Trailer1</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>This spring, students in my Title IX and College Sports class have been studying about Title IX and its application to athletics in the 50th year since Title IX was passed in 1972.  Together we’ve learned about the wonder of Title IX as a comprehensive piece of federal legislation that has, over the years, singularly or in tandem with other equity laws, helped unlock access to educational and athletic opportunities, paving the way for inroads into academic majors and jobs that were once thought of as the exclusive domains of either men or women.  Even as we learn about Title IX’s impact on the ability of students to gain equal access to educational opportunity regardless of gender, the facts about Title IX have also left so many questions unanswered, most specifically why so few Americans in general, and people in college sports in particular - think athletes, coaches, and athletics administrators - know very little about what Title IX is and what it actually requires.</p>

<p>Host: Dr. Ellen J. Staurowsky</p>

<p>Follow us on Instagram! <br />
https://www.instagram.com/talkingtitleix_ic/</p>

<p>An Ithaca College Park School of Communications and High Tops Media Podcast</p>

<p>You can follow for more High Tops Media content on Facebook, Instagram, and Twitter: @hightopsmedia<br />
Check out more podcasts on our website https://hightops.media</p>
]]></description>
            <itunes:duration>374</itunes:duration>
            <link>https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//2023/05/10/Trailer1/</link>
			<itunes:image href='https://talking-title-ix.hightops.media//assets/CoverArtSeason1.jpg'/>
            <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
			
			<itunes:episode>0</itunes:episode>
			<itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
            <itunes:episodeType>trailer</itunes:episodeType>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>